One of your first tasks will be to classify a binary set of data,
你的第一项任务 就是对一个二进制数据集进行分类
images taken during the day or night.
即在白天或夜间拍摄的图像
But before you can complete this task,
但在完成该任务之前
you first have to learn about how images are seen by machines.
你首先要了解机器是如何看到这些图像的
Let's take this image of a car,
以这幅汽车图像为例
this is actually a self-driving car on the road,
它实际上是在道路上的无人驾驶车
and look at how a computer understands it.
我们看看计算机是如何理解这张图的
We'll be working with a grayscale image like this first,
我们首先使用这里的这个灰阶图像
because color adds another layer of complexity.
因为颜色会再增加一层复杂度
But the same general principles will apply, as we'll see soon.
但具体原理是一样的 我们稍后会看到
So when I show you this image you might say,
因此 当我向你展示这幅图像是 你可能说
"Oh it's a picture of a car".
“噢 这是一副汽车的图像”
And it is, but it's also a 2D grid of values,
这是汽车图像 也是一个多个数字组成的二维网格
also known as an array,
即一个阵列
with some width and height. Let me show you what I mean.
包括宽度和高度值 我们来具体看看
This and all digital images are all made of a grid of
这里和所有数字图像都由一个像素网格组成
pixels which are very small units of a single color or intensity.
像素是非常小的单一颜色或密度的单位
And if we zoom in on the image of the car like this area around the wheel,
如果我们放大汽车图像 比如车轮周围的这个区域
we can get a better look at these pixels.
我们可以更清楚地看清楚这些像素
Now you can see it's really starting to look more like a grid.
现在 你可以看到 它看起来更像网格了
Each pixel color in this grid has a corresponding numerical value.
这个网格中 每个像素颜色都有一个对应的数字值
For grayscale images like this,
对于这样的灰阶图像
the value of each pixel ranges from 0 to 255.
每个像素的值从 0 到 255
0 is black, 255 is white,
0 代表黑色 255 代表白色
and gray is anywhere in between.
灰色处于中间的位置
So, a value of around 120 is a medium gray,
因此 120 左右的值是中度灰
in-between black and white,
位于黑色和白色中间
and the value of around 20 will be a very,
20 左右的值是很深的
very dark gray, close to black.
灰色 接近黑色
And, each of these pixels,
这里每个像素
in addition to having a color value,
不仅有颜色值
also has a location,
还有一个位置
x/y in this image grid.
在这个图像网格里的 x/y 值
These axes are a lot like axes for a graph.
这些轴和图表的轴非常类似
Only for digital images,
只是对于数据图像而言
the top left coordinate is at the origin,
左上角的坐标是原点
or the point x equals 0, y equals 0.
即 x=0 y=0
Now, our image of a car is 427 pixels in height and 640 in width,
这里 我们的汽车图像高度为 427 个像素 宽度为 640 个像素
and the pixel locations are on a grid that starts at index zero,
在网格上 像素位置的起点为 0
from 0 to 639 columns and from 0 to 426 rows.
横向位置为 0 到 639 列 纵向位置为 0 到 426 排
As an example, at the location x equals 190 and y equals 375,
例如 在 x 等于 190 y 等于 375 的位置
we have a pixel on this wheel at the bottom left of the image.
这个像素位于车轮上 在图像左下角
The pixel value is 28, a dark,
像素值是 38
dark gray, and you might ask how I know this.
很深的深灰色 你可能想知道我是怎么得到这个值的
Well, in code, we can actually find any single pixel value by location.
在代码中 我们可以根据位置找到每个像素值
So let's do that.
我们做做看
We'll read in our image of a car.
我们读入汽车的图像
But first, I'll input the libraries I need.
但首先 我先导入所需的库
This includes matplotlib.image, which let's us read in any image.
包括 matplotlib.image 它可以帮助我们读入任何图像
You'll also see cv2,
你还看到 cv2
which is a computer vision library,
这是一个计算机视觉库
and you learn more about that soon.
我们马上就会学到
I'll also be using matplotlib qt.
我还会使用 matplotlib qt
qt makes this image pop up in an interactive window when I display it.
Qt 的用处是 显示这幅图像时 会弹出一个互动窗口
So I'll read in the image of our car using matplotlib's 'imread' function,
我使用 matplotlib 的 imread 函数读入这幅汽车图像
and I'll pass in the name of our image file.
导入图像文件的名称
I have the image of our car in an images directory in the same location as this notebook.
汽车图像在图像文件夹中 位置和这个笔记本相同
Next, I'll actually print out some information about this image.
接下来 我会打印出该图像的一些信息
I want to print out its dimensions by referencing image dot shape.
我想引用 image.shape 打印出图像尺寸
Now you can see its height and width in pixels.
现在 你可以看到它的高度和宽度像素值
And we see another value, three,
我们看到了另一个值 3
which corresponds to the number of color channels his image has.
它对应的是这幅图像的颜色通道数量
And we'll learn more about this value soon.
我们后面会学到
For now, we'll convert our image to be grayscale,
现在 我们先把图像转换为灰阶
and I'll convert it to grayscale using our computer vision library.
使用我们的计算机视觉库完成这个操作
For now, know that this has built-in color conversion code,
现在 你要知道 这里有内置的颜色转换代码
like changing an image from red/green/blue color to grayscale.
在这里 把图像从红色/绿色/蓝色转换为灰阶
Then, I'll display this grayscale image.
然后 我会显示灰阶图像
This opens our interactive window.
这里会打开互动窗口
And as I pass over this image with my mouse,
鼠标在图像上方移动时
you can see the x/y location displayed in the bottom left of the screen,
你可以看到在屏幕左下角显示了 x/y 位置
as well as the corresponding pixel value.
还显示了对应的像素值
Down here by the wheel,
下面 轮子这里
we have dark pixel values around 28/29.
我们有一个深色的像素值 大约是 28/29
And up here in the sky, we have some light pixel values,
这里 在天空中 我们有一些浅色的像素值
you can see around 220 or even higher.
你可以看到 大概在 200 左右 甚至更高
And if we go back to our notebook,
如果我们回到笔记本
we can print out the value of a single pixel by accessing it by location.
我们可以根据位置方位单个像素 打印出它的值
I'll say x equals 190 and y equals 375.
例如 x 等于 190 y 等于 375
And I can access that pixel value by looking at
要访问这个像素值 我可以在
that location in our gray image, y comma x.
灰阶图像中查看这个位置 [y,x]
Finally, I'll print out that value,
最后 我打印出这个值
and we can see that it's 28.
我们可以看到 值是 28
Every pixel in an image is just a numerical value,
图像中的每个像素都是个数字值
and we can also change these pixel values.
我们也可以改变这些像素值
We can multiply every single one by a scalar to change how bright the image is,
我们把每个值乘以一个标量 改变图像亮度
we can shift each pixel value to the right or left,
我们可以把每个像素值右移或左移
and many more operations.
还有很多其他操作
Treating images as grids of numbers is the basis for many image processing techniques.
把图像看作数字组成的网格是很多图像处理方法的基础
Most color and shape transformations are done just by
大多数颜色和形状转换 都只需要
mathematically operating on an image and changing it pixel by pixel.
对图像进行数学运算 并逐个像素更改即可